Okay, so let's talk about these three
terms here that sound very similar to one
another, but there is a subtle difference
between them.
Right.
Risk tolerance, risk appetite,
and risk threshold.
All right, so risk tolerance, the basic
definition of, I mean, essentially what
risk tolerance is, the
maximum potential impact of a
risk that stakeholder
organization is willing to take.
So tolerance, what is tolerance?
Whenever you see tolerance, it basically
specifies a range.
And that's really what risk tolerance is.
So, as a simple example, right,
are we going to go behind schedule?
How much behind schedule are we going to
accept?
Right.
So, you know, we'll accept, we've
identified a risk.
We will accept a schedule slippage of 5 to
8%.
Or let's say there's a cost increase.
So as long as a cost doesn't increase by
10%, then that's fine.
We will accept this cost increase of 10%.
So that's our tolerance.
The other term then is this one called
risk appetite, right?
And risk appetite then, again,
the official term, the official
explanation or definition is the maximum
degree of uncertainty the stakeholder of
the organisation is actually willing to
take.
Now, what is appetite?
Appetite is synonymous with, you know,
with food, with being hungry or being full.
I mean, that's really what appetite refers
to.
So in this case, we're talking about
hunger for risk.
Right.
So as a simple example then, like the
example here.
If the reward is really high, we will
accept a higher risk.
Right.
So in that case, then we have a high risk
appetite.
If we're bidding on this contract, it's a
really lucrative contract
for our organization.
It's going to make us, you
know, a lot of money that
have a lot more than what,
you know, any other contract.
However, you know, we have to invest a lot
of money.
There's no guarantee that we're going to
get it.
Even if we invest money
to bid on this contract,
there's no guarantee
we're going to get it.
But because the reward is really high,
we might want to take that risk.
In that case, then, we have a high-risk
appetite in that scenario.
And the other term is this one,
risk threshold.
A risk threshold really refers to both,
tolerance appetite, and it's just
basically showing the
level of exposure of where
the risk, you know, is
going to be addressed.
At what point are we actually going to do
something about it?
And these are a couple of examples of
different.
classification that you could have,
right?
No action, consider, take action.
So, just think as something very,
very simple, like the weather.
We're in the middle of winter,
say, and, you know, we're here,
you know, somewhere where it snows
regularly.
And if someone says that there's a,
10% chance of, 10% chance of a snowstorm,
do we really do anything about it?
Maybe 10% we're not going to do anything
about it, right?
So at that point, we're going to do,
we're going to know.
not going to take any action.
If they say there's a 20% chance of a
snowstorm.
Well, 20% chance, again, probably won't
take any action.
Even up to, I mean, at some point, and
you, each individual will have their calf.
So maybe up to about, say, 40%,
I'm really not going to do anything.
Up to about 40%, 45%, really, you know,
maybe I won't do anything about that.
I won't take any action.
But let's say it's now 50%.
At that point, I might consider it.
Right.
So maybe between, say, 40% and 70% I'll
consider.
All right, maybe there might be a
snowstorm coming through.
Maybe I need to think about it.
But then anything over 70% now,
I'm going to take some kind of action.
Now I'm just going to, I'm going to
prepare as though it's going to snow.
Now we're going to get a snowstorm,
I'm just going to consider that we're
going to get a snowstorm, and so I'm going
to take action at that point.
So just as a very simple example.
So that's really what the risk threshold
refers to, right?
So my level of risk exposure.
So at what point am I going to actually
address the risk or accept the risk?